HAPPY TOGETHER
黎耀辉
Lai Yiu-Fai...
不如我们由头再来过
let's start over.
“不如由头来过”这句话何宝荣的口头禅
Ho Po-Wing always says, "Let's start over,"
我承认这句话对我很有杀伤力
and it gets to me every time.
我们在一起已经很久
We've been together for a while
中间也有分开过
and we break up often...
可是不知为什么每次听见他说这句话
but whenever he says, "Let's start over,"
我就会跟他再走到一起
I find myself back with him.
因为想由头来过 我们离开了香港
In order to start over, we left Hong Kong.
两个人走着走着就来到了阿根廷
We hit the road and ended up in Argentina.
请问瀑布怎么去
Which way to Iguazu?
这路不到瀑布
The waterfall? Iguazu is that way. It's the other way.
又说会看地图 走错路了
Didn't you say you could read a map? We're miles off!
走错路需不需要死呢 走错路不就掉头喽
So what's the big deal? Just turn around and find the right road.
干
Fuck!
买什么车 搭巴士不是好端端罗
Why did we get a car? We should've taken the bus.
这样的废材又开不动
This wreck is useless!
你来开吧
You do it!
有废材都好过没有
This is better than nothing.
现在很多身家咩
We're not rich.
有架车给你坐都好过挤巴士啊 三十多个钟头
And who wants to be stuck in a bus for 30 hours?
旅行是这样的啦
But that's what traveling is about!
我没想着这样子的啊
Not for me it isn't!
下去推推车啊 谢谢
Get out and push, will you?
初初来到阿根廷什么地方也不认识
When we first got here, we had no idea where to go.
有一天何宝荣买了一盏枱灯
Then Po-Wing bought a lamp
我觉得很漂亮
and I really liked it.
我们很想知道灯罩上面的瀑布在哪里
We wanted to find the waterfall on the lamp.
问了很多人才知道是Iguazu
We found out it was at Iguazu.
本来想着去了瀑布就回香港
We planned to see it and then go home
结果我们迷了路
but we lost our way.
喂
Hey!
你去哪儿
Where are you going?
其实到现在我都没搞清楚那天我们去了哪里
I never did find out where we were that day.
我只记得他跟我说 和我在一起的日子好闷
He said being with me is a bore,
不如大家分开一下
that we should take a break...
有机会遇回再由头来过
and perhaps start over again some day.
其实何宝荣的"由头来过"可以有两个意思
"Starting over" means different things to him.
在阿根廷找工作不是那么容易 因为这里不是很多中国人
It's hard to find work in Argentina. There aren't a lot of Chinese around.
跟他分开后我来到布宜洛斯艾利斯
After we broke up, I came to Buenos Aires.
在一间探戈酒吧当接待
I've been working as a doorman at a tango bar.
走开啦
Move it!
欢迎 欢迎
Welcome!
请进 请进
This way!
欢迎 欢迎
Welcome!
请大家快点啦 快点 快点
Go right on in!
欢迎 欢迎 欢迎
Welcome! Welcome!
请进 请进
This way! This way!
里面坐 里面坐
Take a seat inside.
那晚我又碰见何宝荣 我没想过要跟他由头来过
Seeing him again,I realize I don't want to "start over."
我只是想回香港
I just want to go back to Hong Kong.
你要来玩吗
You coming to the game?
怎么样 你应该来 我跟那家伙都在
How about it? You should come. I'll be here with the guys.
辉 你有电话
Fai, telephone.
-我 -电话来个不停
-Me? -They can't keep calling like this.
喂
Hello?
你找我干嘛
What is it?
跑来跑去怎么拍
I said stand still!
笑嘛
Smile!
干 不拍了
Fuck it!
怎么这么久
hey why take you so long
烟
cigarette
的士
Taxi
给我火
give me a light
给我个火
give me light
喂 谁
Hello ? Who?
辉 有电话
Fai! Telephone!
喂
Hello?
是我
Is me
你怎么知道我电话
How did you get my number?
开门呀 何宝荣
Ho Po-Wing, open the door!
开门
Open the door!
怎么样啊 黎耀辉
What's up, Lai Yiu-Fai?
怎么样 何宝荣
What's up, Ho Po-Wing?
进来
Come in.
我干嘛要进来
Why should I?
我有话跟你说
I want to talk to you.
有什么在这儿说
We can talk here.
有要紧的跟你说 进来啊
It's important. Come in!
有什么快点讲啦
Talk!
干嘛呀
What the hell?
说完啦
That's it.
没有啦 走呀
You can go now.
走呀
Go on.
别推我
Don't push me.
推我我揍你的
I'll hit you.
揍我
Really?
你妈的有种就捏死我
Kill me if you got the balls!
仆街仔
You little shit!
我仆街得过你
You think you're any better?
“晚安晚安请进请进”
"Welcome! Welcome! Come in! Come in!"
做什么鸟不去做鸭
Isn't that prostitution?
你理我
That's none of your business!
我不像你 有鬼佬照顾
I'm not like you have white trash taking care of me!
照你老妈
Fuck you.
我什么都没有
I'm broke!
钱又被你花光了
You blew all my money!
我还要回香港
I want to go back to Hong Kong.
没钱怎么回
How can I with no money?
我也不想做啊
You think I like that job?
你有没有后悔跟我一起
Do you regret being with me?
好他妈后悔啊我
You damn well bet I do!
没见你之前我一点也不后悔
I had no regrets till I met you.
现在我他妈的后悔得要死
Now my regrets could kill me!
怎样
Well?
怎样啦
示威 在奚落我
You trying to put me down?
告诉我你混得很好啊
Showing me you're well off?
你混得好关我鸟事
I don't give a shit!
你叫我来干嘛 叫我来干嘛
Why did you ask me to come?
我只是想你陪我一下
I just want to be with you.
我好想你陪我一下
I really do.
嗱
Fuck!
给你
For you.
不喜欢就卖掉
Sell it if you don't like it.
干
Shit!
又怎么啦
What is it now?
可不可以先把表还我
Can I have the watch back?
坐后面啦 后面没这么光
Let's sit in the back. It's darker.
干嘛 我现在见不得人啊
You don't want to be seen with me?
你觉得自己的样子很见得人啊
Not with your face looking like that.
你看到的咩 我以为你看不见喎
So you can see! I didn't think you'd noticed.
整天一声不响 我以为你没察觉喎
You didn't say anything. I thought you couldn't see.
原来你看到我被人打的
So you noticed I got beaten up.
想我讲什么 不打也被人打了
What do you want me to say? What happened happened.
喂大佬 一场朋友啊你都问候一句吧
We're friends, aren't we? Couldn't you say something nice?
我这么大第一次被人打都是因为你啊
It happened because of you.
别说为了我 别赖得就赖
Don't blame it on me.
我没说要那只手表 你要拿给我而已
I didn't ask for that watch.
那你又收下
But you took it.
你应该当面给回我吖嘛
You could've given it back.
当面给回我我怎会被人打
Then I wouldn't have gotten beat up.
是不是想被人打多一顿
You want some more?
要不要我陪你回去
Want me to take you home?
省点啦你
Don't bother!
只晓得欺负我
You're always bullying me.
喂你家呢 你家在哪边
You live here?
你在这儿等我
Wait here.
给回你
Here you go.
喂
Hey!
怎样
What now?
给支烟来吸
Got a cigarette?
火呢
A light?
你以后别再找我
Don't come looking for me again.
喂 是 辉
Hello ? Yes, Fai ?
他不久前走开了
He left a while ago.
不久前而已
It was a while ago.
不客气 再见
Sure. Don't mention it. Bye. See you later.
黎耀辉
Lai Yiu-Fai!
Lai Yiu-Fai...
不如我们由头来过
let's start over.
这儿都几好呀
This is a nice place.
住了多久
How long have you lived here?
几个月
A few months.
怎么住得这么偏
It's not exactly centrally located.
便宜点
It's cheap.
也是的
Of course.
天花板很高看 出去风景也不错
Nice high ceiling. Good view outside.
这灯你没丢
You still have that lamp?
以为早给你抛了
I thought you'd have thrown it away.
你最终有没有去看瀑布
Did you ever get to see the falls?
没有 你呢
No, did you?
没有
No.
等你嘛
I was waiting for you.
待我好了我们一起去好吗
We'll go when I'm better.
到时候再说
We'll see.
今晚你睡这边
Sleep here tonight.
-那你呢 -我睡沙发
-What about you ? -I'll take the sofa.
欢迎 欢迎
Welcome.
欢迎 欢迎 里面坐 里面坐
Welcome.Welcome.Come in
很好很好 再来一张
Good. Let's do one more.
低一点
Lower a bit
三 笑
One, two, three, smile!
近一点 近一点啊
Closer together now.
一 二 三 好
One, two, three. Great!
谢谢
Thank you
-你什么都不做只会吃 滚开啦 -好啦 好啦!
-You do nothing but eat! Scram! -Okay, okay!
何宝荣 吃饭啦
Hey, Ho Po-Wing. Let's eat.
吃饭啦 起来吧
Get up and eat.
夹块鸡来尝下
Give me some chicken.
我是不是很脏啊
Am I very dirty?
医生说不能洗澡嘛
The doctor said no showers.
这么多咬痕的
What are all these bites?
大哥你张床几多蚤子啊
Your bed has fleas!
下雨嘛 一下雨总是这样子
That's what happens when it rains.
好天气时嗮下床盖啊 被单吖嘛
When the weather's better, you should disinfect the bed.
咬死人咩
I don't want to get bitten to death.
抬高手
Lift your arm.
喂喂痛啊我的手
Hey, that hurts.
-肉来的 -又说脏了
-Be gentle. -You said you were dirty.
是吖嘛 抬得那么高
You're scrubbing too hard!
也喷下那边啦
Spray over there too.
自己睡那边的嘛
Spray where you sleep.
-干什么 -有没烟
-What? -Cigarettes.
那边不是还有
Over there.
都他妈的没了
They're all gone.
-下去给你买 -不用了 睡觉啦
-I'll go buy some. -Don't bother. Go to sleep.
-给我两包香烟 -好的
-Give me two packs. -Okay.
-谢谢 -再见
-Thank you. -Bye.
喂 干嘛有床不睡
What are you doing? You got your own bed.
我喜欢
I like it like this.
不觉得两个人睡一张沙发很挤
The sofa's too small for two.
不觉得 这样蛮舒服啊
No. I think it's quite comfy.
干嘛咬我
Why did you bite me?
我饿
I'm hungry.
你是不是要睡沙发
You want this sofa?
干什么呢
Come on.
-那我睡床了 -别说这么多话睡觉啦
-Fine, I'll take the bed. -Just go back to sleep.
要不你睡床上我睡沙发
If you want the bed, I'll stay here.
别像八婆似的好不好啊
Quit whining, will you?
-喂 -OK 我睡床
-Hey! -Okay, I'll sleep on the bed.
你是不是那么没人情味
Why can't you be nice?
都说很挤罗
The bed's too small.
什么挤呢
It's not.
我睡你上边这样就不挤
I can sleep on top of you.
这样子睡 这样子睡
We can sleep like this.
你是不是睡床上啊嗱
So you're gonna sleep on the bed?
是不是真这样子对我
Don't be like that.
干什么嘛
What now?
就这样子睡啦 好不好啊
Let's sleep like this, okay?
好 你睡
Okay, let's go to sleep.
别动 大家这样睡
Stop tossing around. We'll sleep like this.
-你别搞我 -谁搞你 你别搞我
-You better not touch me. -Me touch you? You better not touch me.
睡觉
Good night. Let's sleep.
别搞啊 手痛啊
Watch my hand. It hurts.
老板
Hey!
给我个意大利千酪比萨
Gimme a mozzarella pizza.
那不勒斯比萨饼
Neapolitan?
-意大利干酪 -那不勒斯比萨
-Mozzarella. -Neapolitan?
不 意大利干酪比萨
No, mozzarella.
-意大利干酪 -对
-Mozzarella? -Yes.
快点啦
Move it, fatty!
介绍中国女生给我认识
Find me a Chinese girl
-我请你吃 -拿来
-and I'll deliver for free. -Give it here!
要爆乳的
I want one with big tits!
觉不觉得有什么不同
Notice anything different?
我真是警告你 别再耍花样
I'm warning you, no more of your games.
-喂 顶不顺了 -什么顶不顺了
-I can't take it anymore! -Come on!
走一下啦 整天困在那里 蛇都死啦
Keep moving! Morning exercise is good for you.
好冷啊 以后再来啦
It's cold. Let's do this tomorrow!
冷什么呢 神经 走一下啦
It's not that cold. Keep moving!
-不过又真的好冷嗬 -那怎么样啊
-You're right, it's freezing. -Now what?
好啦 回去啦 回去啦
Okay, let's go back.
干
Fuck!
黎耀辉
Lai Yiu-Fai?
你怎么啦
How do you feel?
好辛苦
Terrible.
哇真的好烫
You're burning up.
当然烫
Of course I am.
你说你是不是在耍我
What were you thinking?
天寒地冻的 有觉不睡走去晨运
Why did you drag me out in the cold? It was freezing.
怎么知道你这么弱 走两步你就病了
I never thought a little jog would make you sick.
怎么样啊 起不起得到床啊
Can you get up?
起不起得到床又怎样
What for?
煮饭罗
To cook something.
我肚子好饿啊 我两天没吃东西了
I'm starving. I haven't eaten for two days!
就快饿死啦
I'm starving to death!
是不是人来的 你问下你自己
Are you not human or what?
病到这样叫我起身煮饭给你吃
You ask a sick man to cook for you?
你妈的 快上
Faster, you son of a bitch!
发达了今天
We're rich!
票呢票呢票呢 收钱
Where's the ticket? I'll claim the money!
谢谢
Thanks.
咖啡
Coffee.
这步吖嘛 每次总是忘记这一步
You keep forgetting that step.
自己先练习一下
Try it by yourself.
成天都不记得上一步
You keep forgetting that last step.
交叉转那边你到这边做什么
Cross your feet and go the other way.
可以啦
I got it.
是不是啊
You sure?
这里试一下
Okay, try it here.
一
One...
二
Two...
三
Three...
四
Four...
五
来吧 我们走
Come on, let's go!
别说了 我们回家吧
Stop it, let's go home.
来吧
Come on, come on.
我们会过得很好
We'll have a good time.
喂
Hello?
喂 这么巧
What a coincidence.
上街呀
You out for a walk?
在等你下班啊傻佬
I was waiting for you, silly.
喂 怎么不通知一声
Hey, why didn't you tell me?
通知一声什么
Tell you what?
打电话去你旧公司 说你没有做了
I called you at work. They said you'd quit.
也不通知一下
You didn't say a thing.
不做了有什么好说的
What's there to say?
喂 你是不是打得他很惨了
Did you hurt him bad?
不讲啦
I'm not telling you.
讲啦 你不讲我睡不着觉的
Come on! I won't be able to sleep if you don't tell me.
睡不着就上街喽 你这么喜欢上街
Then go for a stroll. You like going out.
喂喂 那我睡不着你也睡不着是不是
If I don't sleep, you don't sleep.
-你上了街我怎么会睡不着 -说来听听呀
-I'll sleep fine if you're out walking. -Why won't you tell me? Tell me!
-不说 -讲啦
-No. -Tell me!
不讲啊 好烦啊你
No! You're so annoying!
- 辉啊 -什么
-Fai! -What?
- 咖啡杯没了快点 -哦
-We're out of coffee cups, quick! -Okay.
-面啊 -OK 弄多两杯咖啡
-Noodles! -All right. Two more cups of coffee.
单听声音就知道这是个厨房
You can tell it's a kitchen by the noise.
如果你听得仔细一点你就可以分得出来 哪些人在吵架哪些人在炒菜
Listen carefully and you can hear who's cooking and who's just cursing.
有人在讲电话 有人在洗碗
Some are talking on the phone. Some are washing dishes.
我问你在做什么啊
What are you doing?
吃了东西没有
Have you eaten?
我问你吃了东西没有
I said have you eaten yet?
打包回来给你吃罗
I'll bring something back for you.
想吃什么
What do you want to eat?
别玩啦 想吃什么啊
Don't play games.
你买什么我吃什么罗
Just tell me. Whatever you bring is fine.
就这样子吧
Okay. Ciao.
这个人很喜欢讲电话
This guy loves talking on the phone...
听得出来他的语气很愉快
and his voice always sounds pleasant.
对方一定是他喜欢的人
He must be talking to someone he likes.
还没走啊 其他人都收工了 明天再洗啊
Everyone's gone. Finish that tomorrow.
我说其他人已经收工了 明天再洗啊
I said leave it for tomorrow.
反正我没地方去先弄完
It's okay. I have nothing else to do.
你不是来玩的吗
Aren't you here on vacation?
钱花完了 先赚钱呐
Yeah, but I ran out of money.
吃不吃
You want some?
我不要
I'm okay.
不用钱的
It's on me.
好好好
Okay.
好不好吃
How is it?
好吃
Great.
你慢慢吃 我走先
Enjoy it. I'm going.
走啦
See you.
辉 打麻将吗
Fai, wanna play mahjong?
别搞我 你们自己玩
No, count me out. You guys have fun.
数目不对吗
Pay's not right?
没有啊 算算还要待多久
No, just figuring out how long I have to work.
这边用钱好贵
Things are pricey here.
你在看地图啊 去哪里
You reading a map? Where are you going?
想着去瀑布玩一下
I want to see the falls.
好玩啊
That's a fun place.
你去过
Have you been there?
-没有啊 -没去过又说好玩
-No. -Then how do you know it's fun?
-就是没有去过才好玩嘛 你一个人去啊
-Anywhere new is fun. You going alone?
跟朋友
With a friend.
好羡慕你噢 我都不知道在这边要待多久
I envy you. Looks like I'm stuck here.
你想去哪儿
Where do you want to go?
不知道啊 能走多远就走多远
I don't know. As far as I can.
你家人不理你吗
Doesn't your family worry?
我自己出来的
I'm here on my own.
他们也不知道我在哪里
They don't know where I am.
想过要回去吗
Planning to go back?
不开心才出来的嘛
I left 'cause I wasn't happy.
没有想通以前回去也没什么意思啊
I need to figure things out before I go back.
不跟你讲啦 你玩得开心啊
Enough about that. Have a good time.
真是不行 今天好旺啊 明天先吧
I can't. We're really busy. How about tomorrow?
星期三不是更好 看戏便宜一半
Movies are half price on Wednesday.
现在怎么请假
I can't take a day off!
阿辉 赶快帮我拿三个鸡蛋过来
Fai, bring me three eggs!
哦 你等等
Hang on.
喂
Hello?
找你的
It's for you.
喂 同事罢了
Hello? That was a coworker.
回来再跟你说
We'll talk when I get back.
我工作先了再见
I've got to go. Bye.
忙死了你还在打电话
We're busy and you're on the phone!
-干嘛啊你 一大早弄醒人 -你翻我东西干嘛
-What's the matter with you? -You were going through my stuff!
我干嘛翻你东西 你神经病啊你
Why would I? Are you nuts?
没翻我东西我柜子会这么乱
My drawer's a mess!
喂 你看看我的手
Look at my hands!
我的手这样拿什么翻 用口翻啊
You think I did it with my mouth?
再搞我东西 我打断你的腿
Do it again and I'll break your legs!
打呀有种你打呀
Fine! Go ahead!
来去手没有了 连脚也不要啦
Then they'll match my hands!
神经病 我翻你柜子不如翻你衣柜
Think I went through your closet too?
你要再碰我东西就滚
If you do it again, you can just get out!
是你说的叫我滚
You mean it?
来替我穿裤子穿鞋子 我现在滚 来呀
Help me get dressed. I'll leave now!
你舍得滚你舍得滚
You will?
-滚了睡街上 -我宁愿睡街上
-You'll be sleeping on the street! -I'd rather sleep on the street!
你别不舍得
Don't you regret it!
神经病
Lunatic!
他泡你的 还是你泡他
Did he pick you up or did you pick him up?
-有没有什么 -什么
-Did you do it? -What?
-你晓得我说什么 -什么啊
-You know what. -What?
什么嘛
You know!
什么什么
I know what?
你管得了我 你没跟别人睡过
What's it to you? Haven't you slept with other guys?
那么以后你别问我 我也别问你
Fine. You don't ask me, and I won't ask you.
-喂 -你别再来看我揍你
Stay away! I'll beat you up!
-可以可以 -过那边睡
-Okay, okay. -Sleep over there!
火气这么大啊近来嘛
You get so touchy sometimes.
问少少东西而已 不是心中有鬼不就告诉我罗
I was just gonna ask if there was something on your mind.
这么燥
Why are you in such a bad mood?
-起身 -干什么啊
-Get up! -What now? What is it?
又说要睡觉
Didn't you want to sleep?
这么喜欢问问题嘛 那么有兴趣知道我的事情嘛
-Since you're so fond of questions...
我现在想知道你跟什么人睡过
tell me who you've slept with!
好像是我先问你跟他有没有睡过 你怎么问我
I believe I asked first. Why are you asking me?
你喜欢烦我嘛
Now it's my turn.
我现在想知道你跟哪些人睡过
Who have you slept with?
-你真要知道 -说呀
-You want to know? -Yes.
喂 现在三点半
It's already half past three.
我男朋友多过天上繁星
I've had so many boyfriends,
我怕讲到九点半你上班我还没讲完
I'd still be counting when you leave for work.
无所谓 我现在睡不着
I don't mind. I'm not sleepy.
你说啊 慢慢说
Take your time.
我不喜欢说
I don't want to.
-你这个死家伙 -喂喂
-You little slut! -Hey! Hey!
够了喎 够了喎
Stop it! Stop it!
你滚
Get out!
认真的吗
You mean it?
-没空跟你开玩笑 -别碰我
-Yes, I mean it. -Okay! Don't touch me!
-我自己走 -自己走呀
-I'll go! -Go!
打得我那么重 明知道我残废掉还要
You know I'm injured and you're giving me bruises.
走啦
Get out!
整晚没得睡
Can't get any sleep around here!
冷死你
Go on and freeze to death!
喂 多少次啊
So, how many times?
说嘛
Tell me.
什么多少次
How many times what?
你跟他做了多少次
How many times did you two do it?
做得出不怕认嘛
If you did it, admit it.
很多次 满意了吧
A lot. All right?
还有跟谁呢
Were there others?
楼下保安的有没有啊
Did you do the janitor downstairs?
我不是你
I'm not like you.
喂
Hey.
还要做多久
Will it take much longer?
我是辉
This is Fai.
何宝荣先生在不在
Is Mr. Ho Po-Wing there?
谢谢 拜拜
Thank you. Bye.
那么黑也不开灯
It's so dark. Why don't you turn the light on?
去哪儿了
Where have you been?
买烟罗
Buying cigarettes.
穿得那么漂亮去买烟
All dressed up?
经常都不上街 穿好一点下去逛逛
I don't get out often, so I dress up when I do.
买那么多烟干嘛
Why did you buy so many?
路过就买 免得你半夜跑去买
To save you from having to go out for them at night.
到哪儿去了
Where have you been?
横坚闲着 就下街走走
For a walk. I was bored.
吃宵夜吗
Want some food?
你觉得很闷
Are you really bored here?
你是不是闲着没事找架吵吗
Do we have to go through this again?
我下去走走也不可以
If I want to go out, I'll go out!
可以
Fine.
一直都是你喜欢怎么样就怎样
You always do what you like anyway.
那你今晚是不是睡这边啊 你睡这里的话我睡那边喎
You taking the bed tonight? I'll take the sofa.
不是
I'll take the sofa.
怎么知道你回不回来睡
I just wasn't sure you were coming back.
吃宵夜
Eat!
看着点
Watch out!
抢他的球
Get the ball.
传球
Pass it.
干
Damn it!
别打架
Cool it!
别打别打
Stop it!
改天再玩
That's enough for today.
有件事情我一直没说给何宝荣听
One thing I never told Ho Po-Wing...
其实我不想他太早复原
was that I didn't want him to recover too quickly.
他受伤的那阵子是我和他最开心的时光
Those were our happiest days.
你就不能先把房租交了吗
Look, just pay me the rent.
你要干嘛
What do you want? Can't you see I'm cooking?
-看不见我在煮菜吗 -煮菜也得交房租
You still gotta pay the rent!
我现在可什么都给不了
I can't pay you anything right now!
我别的待缴费用还多的是呢
Not now and that's that.
你拿了我的护照去哪儿
Did you take my passport?
没拿过
No.
没 没拿我怎么会找不到
No? Then why can't I find it?
我哪知道
No idea.
你好给回本护照我
Give me back my passport.
-你要护照来干嘛 -你理我
-What do you want it for? -That's none of your business!
我不会还给你的
I'm not giving it back.
-你想找什么 -你知道我想找什么
-What are you looking for? -You know very well.
你好拿回出来
Give it back!
你要我讲多少次
How many times do I have to tell you?
我是不会给回你的
I'm not giving it back.
来啊 打啊
Yeah, hit me!
打啊 打啊
Hit me! Hit me!
-打啊 -干
-Hit me! -Fucker!
今天怎么不打麻将
Not playing mahjong today?
不想打就不打
I don't feel like it.
你要不要去喝一杯呀
Wanna go for a drink?
别吐嘛
You drank too much.
走走走 我扶你我扶你
Come on, let me help you.
哪边
Where's your place?
有没有搞错 这样抱着我怎么打球
Damn it. Let me go.
别打架
No fighting!
不准用手碰球
No hands!
这边
Over here!
嗨 陪我去看电影
Want to see a movie with me?
我不看电影 看电影我头痛
I don't like movies. They give me a headache.
神经病
Weirdo.
对 我神经病
Right, I'm a weirdo.
其实她蛮骚的
She's pretty hot.
那你不陪她看电影
Then why not go out with her?
我不喜欢她的声音
I don't like her voice.
我喜欢女人的声音喔
I like women's voices...
很低沉的那一种
deep and low.
也不一定啦
Well, actually it depends.
反正就是听了以后 心跳会很快很快的那一种
What I mean is, I like voices that make my heart beat faster.
你呢 你喜欢女孩子什么声音啊
What about you? What kind of woman's voice do you like?
无所谓 喜欢就好
I don't really care.
累了就回去睡
Go home if you're tired.
不会啊 我在听那两个人讲话
No, I'm listening to those guys talking.
那么远你也听得到
From this far away?
还好啦 不懂得他们在讲什么
I'm not sure what they're saying
等一下就会打架了吧
but they're gonna fight.
你的耳朵好厉害喎
You have really good hearing.
可能习惯了吧
It's a habit of mine.
我小时候眼睛生病 看不见东西都用耳朵在听
I had bad eyes as a kid. I couldn't see well, so I listened.
后来花很多钱把眼睛医好
My family spent a lot to fix my sight,
可是习惯就改不掉啊
but old habits die hard.
有的时候我觉得
Sometimes I think
耳朵比眼睛还重要
ears are more important than eyes.
很多东西用耳朵听比用眼睛看好
You "see" better with your ears.
就好像一个人很不开心会装得很开心
You can act happy...
可是声音就装不了啊
but your voice reveals the truth.
仔细一听就知道了嘛
Listen closely and you can tell.
是吗
Really?
就像你的声音啊 现在就很不开心啊
Just like your voice now tells me you're not happy.
知不知道后面那两个人在说什么
So what are they saying over there?
我试一下
Let me try.
好耶
Goal!
三块
Three bucks!
小张
Chang!
-钱都收了 -五块
-How much did we win? -Five bucks.
你两块
Two for you.
为什么我两块你三块
Why do you get three?
好 那你三块
Okay, three for you.
整班人一起 我发觉小张的声音最大
Chang had the liveliest voice amongst us.
下午在小巷踢球我觉得很热
It got pretty hot playing soccer in the alley.
那年的夏天过得好快
That summer went by very fast.
来来来干一杯 谢谢你的照顾
A toast to friendship. Thanks for everything.
储够钱了
You saved up enough?
-对呀 -恭喜了
-Yeah. -Congratulations.
跟着去哪里
Where are you going next?
往南走啊去一个叫Ushuaia的地方
South to Ushuaia.
很冷的喎去那边干嘛
It's cold there. Why do you want to go?
听说那边是世界尽头所以想去看一看
They say it's the end of the world. I'd like to see it.
你去过没有
You ever been there?
听人说那儿有个灯塔
I heard there's a lighthouse down there.
很多失恋的人都喜欢去那边
People who are heartbroken go there...
说可以把不开心的东西留下
to leave their sadness behind.
现在还有没有人这样
Do people still do that?
不知道呢 有吧
Maybe, I don't know.
讲几句话
Say something.
说什么
What?
你是我这边唯一的朋友
You're my only friend here.
留个纪念嘛
It'll be a memento.
我不喜欢拍照
I don't like pictures.
-不知道说什么 -随便啦
I don't know what to say. Whatever.
什么都可以讲心里面的话就可以
Anything from the heart.
不开心也可以讲嘛
Even something sad.
我可以帮你留在世界的尽头
I'll take it to the end of the world.
-我没有不开心 -那就讲开心的
-I am not sad. -Something cheerful then.
好啦你自己讲 我去玩
All right, you go ahead. I'm gonna dance.
你还好吧
Are you okay?
要不要送你上去
Want me to help you upstairs?
我没事
I'm all right.
真的可以吗
You sure?
你走先吧
You go on now.
那我走了
Goodbye then.
你自己照顾你自己
Take care of yourself.
希望有机会可以再见到你
I hope we'll meet again someday.
你闭上眼
Close your eyes.
-干嘛 -闭上眼先
-Why? -Close your eyes.
-你知不知道你很像一个人 -谁
-You know who you look like? -Who?
盲侠
The blind swordsman.
开玩笑
Very funny.
玩得开心点
Have fun.
以前我不喜欢去公厕找人 因为嫌脏
I never used to pick up men in filthy public toilets.
最近久不久都会去一下 贪那边够方便
These days I do. It's convenient.
我想不到会在那边碰上何宝荣
I didn't think I'd see Po-Wing there.
之后我就没再去过
I've never gone back since.
我一直都以为我跟何宝荣很不同
I always thought I was different from Po-Wing.
怎知道原来寂寞起来的时候 个个都一样
Turns out lonely people are all the same.
在离开香港之前 我从公司拿走一笔钱
Before I left Hong Kong, I stole some money from work.
这份工作是我父亲介绍的
My father got me that job.
老板是他的好朋友
The boss was an old friend of his.
来了阿根廷这么久我不停在工作
I've been working nonstop since I got here.
很想有一天能将钱还给人家
Someday I want to return the money
亦很想跟父亲说声对不起
and apologize to my father.
喂 爸
Hello? Dad?
阿辉啊
This is Fai.
阿根廷十二月还是好热
December in Argentina is very hot.
那天我不用上班
It's my day off
我很想着写张圣诞卡给他
I started writing my father a Christmas card,
怎么知道越写越长
but it turned into a long letter.
除了对不起之外
Apart from saying sorry,
我还讲了好多他一直想知道 但又不敢问的事情
I told him things he'd been afraid to ask about.
我希望他可以当我是个朋友 给我由头来过
I hoped he'd treat me as a friend and give me a chance to start over.
那些臭猪真重
Those damn pigs are breaking my back.
累死我了
I'm sick and tired of this.
因为想赚多些钱
To boost my income,
我去了屠房那边工作
I've started working in a slaughterhouse.
除了工钱高之外
The pay's much better
时间也都很适合我
and the hours suit me fine.
晚上开工白天睡觉
Work all night, sleep all day.
我开始跟回香港时间
I'm back on Hong Kong time.
喂 我啊
Hello? It's me.
没多久何宝荣又打电话来
Po-Wing called soon after.
他藉口说要拿回护照
His excuse was he wanted his passport back.
其实我也想给回他
I didn't mind returning it.
但是我不想跟他见面
I just didn't want to see him.
因为我怕听到他那句口头禅
I dreaded hearing what he always says.
最近我又开始睡不着觉
I'm having trouble sleeping again.
那早看电视我才发觉
Watching TV that morning I realized
原来香港跟阿根廷在地球的两边
that Hong Kong and Argentina are on opposite sides of the world.
不晓得倒转的香港会是什么样子呢
I wonder how Hong Kong looks upside down.
你可以表达你的感受或意见
...you can express your feelings or opinions.
你最近很忙吗
Have you been busy lately?
东北风 2 级 汕头 东南风 2 级
Northeast wind, grade 2. Shantou, south-southeast wind, grade 2.
商业一台
Commercial 1...
逮捕了两名男子以跟进调查
...arrested two men to facilitate the investigation.
警方认为
The police believe that...
因为不想留在家
Since I don't want to stay at home,
所以很多时候假期我也会回屠房开工
I work overtime at the slaughterhouse.
我必须要承认何宝荣那句话是很有杀伤力
Po-Wing's words still get to me,
但是我真不想再继续下去
but this time I won't let them hurt me.
喂
Hello.
对
Yes.
不 阿辉没在这儿住了 他搬走了 拜拜
No, Fai doesn't live here anymore. He moved. Bye.
我很快就储够钱回香港
I soon saved enough to go home.
在离开阿根廷之前
Before I left Argentina
我决定再去瀑布一次
I decided to try to see the falls again.
虽然兜兜转转走了很多冤枉路
I lost my way and wandered around for a while...
我终于来到Iguazu
but I finally reached Iguazu.
那天我很难过
I felt very sad.
因为我始终都觉得 站在瀑布下面的应该有两个人
I always thought there should be two of us standing here.
一九九七年一月
It's January 1997.
我终于来到世界的尽头
I finally arrive at the end of the world.
这里是美洲大陆南面的最后一个灯塔
This is the southernmost lighthouse in South America.
再过去就是南极
Beyond this is the South Pole.
突然之间我很想回家
Suddenly I feel like going home.
我答应过阿辉把他的不开心留在这里
I promised Fai I'd leave his sadness here.
我不知道那天晚上他讲过什么
I don't know what he said that night.
可能是录音机坏了
Maybe the recorder broke
什么声音都没有
I can't hear anything on the tape.
只有两下很奇怪的声音
Just some strange noises...
好像一个人在哭
like someone sobbing.
在我回台湾之前的一个晚上 我又回到布宜洛斯艾利斯
I return to Buenos Aires the night before leaving for Taiwan.
我很想跟阿辉说声再见
I want to say goodbye to Fai,
不过没有人知道他去了哪里
but nobody knows where he is.
离开的时候天开始亮
Dawn is breaking as I leave.
台北现在应该是晚上
It must be night in Taipei.
不知道辽宁街的夜市开了没有
I wonder if the Liao Ning night market has started.
中共中央领导人邓小平
Chinese leader Deng Xiaoping
是在昨天晚上九点零八分病逝在北京三零一医院
died last night in a Beijing hospital.
享年九十三岁
He was 93.
中共中央电视台直到今天凌晨才发布邓小平的死讯
The announcement was made by PRC Central TV early this morning.
在台北起床已经是下午
It's afternoon when I wake up in Taipei.
在一九九七年二月二十日 我回到地球这一边
It's February 20, 1997. I'm back on this side of the world.
过来尝尝我们的肉丸很好吃
Good food here.
-你要吃什么 -有什么好吃的
-What'll it be? -What's good?
招牌面还有米糕臭豆腐都很好吃
Our special meatballs, sticky rice and fried tofu are all tasty.
-你要点什么 -点了 点过了
-What'll you have? -I've ordered already.
米糕一碗
One sticky rice.
我们的东西不要钱啊
You have to pay for that!
我看你就要人家的
I bought this somewhere else, okay?
好啦 去那边啦
Hush! Leave the customer alone!
那你不要吃嘛
Eat it and shut up!
我买了我付了钱耶
Is this how you treat customers?
干什么啦 走开啦
What's your problem? Leave him alone.
神经病 去那边
You're crazy! Get back to work!
汤要吗 好 马上
More soup? Right away.
两位美女进去坐 里边坐
Please sit down. Special dumplings and sticky rice.
-请问有没有电话 -有电话在后面你从那边走过去
-Do you have a phone? -Over there. Come around.
在我回香港之前 我在台北停了一晚
I stayed in Taipei before returning to Hong Kong.
我走了去辽宁街 那晚那边很热闹
I visited the Liao Ning night market. It was very lively.
我见不到小张 我见到他的家人
I didn't see Chang, but I saw his family.
离开时我拿了他一张相片 因为我不知道要等到几时才会再见到他
I took Chang's picture because I didn't know when I'd see him again.
但我可以肯定 如果我想见他的话
What I do know is... if I want to see him...
起码我知道在哪儿可以找到他
I know where to find him.